A Guide to the University of Virginia, Dean of the Curry School of Education, General Records, 1920-1935
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia, Dean of the Curry School of Education, General Records 1920-1935
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-10/1/1.771
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer from the Curry School of Education, University of Virginia on September 14, 1977.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of general records of the Office of the Dean of the Curry School of Education during the tenure of John L. Manahan, including correspondence and related papers concerning admissions, appointments, degree recipients, faculty, scholarships and testing.
Contents List
- Bureau of Appointments- Candidates for Placement, A-O, 3 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 1)
- Bureau of Appointments- Candidates for Placement, P-Z, 2 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 2)
- Bureau of Appointments- Placement Service, Requests and Replies for Personnel, 6 folders, 1931-1935 February (Folder 3)
- Department of the Interior- Bureau of Education: Circulars- City School, High School Education Letter, Legislative Circular, Rural School Letter, Summer School Letter, Vocational Letter, and Miscellaneous Circulars, 1914, n.d. (Folder 4)
- Education School Conference and Dinner Material- Lists, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
- Education School Conference and Dinner Material- Conference re, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
- Education School Conference and Dinner Material- University of Virginia Alumni Dinners, 1922 November 29 and 1923 November 29, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
- Education School Conference and Dinner Material- Virginia Education Conference Handbooks, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
- Education School Conference and Dinner Material- Newspaper Clippings re, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
- Education School- General Correspondence, 1913, 1920-1925 (Folder 4)
- Education School- General Manuscript Material, 1920-1930, n.d. (Folder 5)
- Education School- General Printed Material, 1919-1926, n.d. (Folder 5)
- Educational Testing- Geometry Tests, and Mathematics Tests, 2 folders, n.d. (Folder 5)
- Educational Testing- Latin Tests, 1916-1926, n.d. (Folder 6)
- Educational Testing- Intelligence Tests, 2 folders, 1918-1932 (Folder 6)
- Graduate Studies- Correspondence and Degree Papers, A-C, 1920-1925 (Folder 6)
- Graduate Studies- Correspondence and Degree Papers, D-Z, 1920-1925 (Folder 7)
- Graduate and Undergraduate Studies- Correspondence and Degree Papers, A-Z, 1920-1925 (Folder 7)
- "School of Childhood" Plans and Proposals- Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Folder 7)
- "School of Childhood" Plans and Proposals- Manahan's Notes, 1922-1923 (Folder 7)
- Scholarships- State Teacher's Applications and Awards, A-C, 4 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 7)
- Scholarships- State Teacher's Applications and Awards, C-K, 9 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 8)
- Scholarships- State Teacher's Applications and Awards, L-S, 9 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 9)
- Scholarships- State Teacher's Applications and Awards, S-Y, 6 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 10)
- Scholarships- Du Pont or other general- Applications and Awards, A-Z 2 folders, 1920-1936 (Folder 10)
- Scholarships- State Teacher's, Du Pont, General- Correspondence, 1920- 1936 (Folder 11)
- Scholarships- State Teacher's, Du Pont, General- Lists of applicants and awards, Policy Statement, 1920- 1936 (Folder 11)
- States Teaching Certification Requirements, Correspondence and Printed Material re, A-Z, 3 folders, 1918-1926 (Folder 11)
- States Teaching Certification Requirements, Virginia- Correspondence and Printed Material, 1918-1926 (Folder 11)
- States Teaching Certification Requirements- Correspondence, General Printed Material, Lists, 1918-1926 (Folder 11)
- States Colleges Accredited- Correspondence and Printed Material, A-Z, 2 folders, 1920-1928 (Folder 12)
- Teaching Agencies- Associated Schools Service and Southern Teachers Organization: Correspondence and Applications, 1925 (Folder 12)
- Virginia State Teachers Association- Minutes of Meetings, Printed Material, 1925-1927 (Folder 12)
- Virginia State Teachers Association- Minutes of Meetings, Printed Material, 1925-1927 (Folder 12)
- Virginia Education- Miscellaneous Correspondence, Printed Materials, News Clippings, 1926-1927 (Folder 12)
- Virginia Education Association- Correspondence, and Printed Material, 1926-1927, n.d. (Folder 12)
- Virginia Journal of Education- Correspondence and Printed Material, 1926-1927 (Folder 12)
- Virginia State Board of Education- Printed Material, 1915-1925 (Folder 12)